

As'ad Saleh Umar

Software engineer: full-stack web & mobile development

Website ∕









SUMMARY

Software engineer with 5+ years of professional experience. Strong team player, leader, and teacher. Experienced in the full-stack development cycle from design to deployment. Years of hands-on experience in JavaScript, ReactJS, and Flutter ecosystem. Loves teaching and sharing technical skills.

Management	Act as an engineering manager and technical leader for the front-end & mobile development team.
Front-end	HTML and CSS (Tailwind, Styled Components, SASS). JavaScript and TypeScript. Frameworks & Libs: React, NextJS, Remix, Redux, TanStack, tRPC, etc.
Mobile dev	React Native, Flutter, Android (Java).
Back-end & DB	NodeJS & Go. Postgres, Supabase, Firebase, Redis, MySQL. Prisma ORM.
Git proficiencies	Implement branching strategies, branch permissions, and CI/CDs. I helped my team to resolve complicated Git problems.
Extras	Manage app distribution using Google Play Console, Firebase, and Microsoft App Center. Work in an agile environment. Firm understanding of both REST & GraphQL API.
Language	Native in Bahasa Indonesia, good in English.

WORK EXPERIENCES

MainstreamLabs, US (Remote) Full Time | June 2023 - January 2024, 8 months

MainstreamLabs is a startup with a vision to provide a governance platform for web3 organizations. Tech stack includes: NextJS 14 (RSC), Stripe API, NodeJS, Supabase.

• Full-Stack Developer.

I helped the team to polish the previous app, which is a twitter-like web3 app for users to manage & follow their interest in available DAOs. I also helped the team develop a new app -a notification service SaaS-from scratch to production in record time.

Infradigital Nusantara, Indonesia, Full Time | April 2020 - June 2023, 3 years & 3 months Infradigital is a B2B Edtech Startup providing financial, compliance & supply chain services to over 20,000 low-income schools. I was a part of the engineering team, tasked with developing & maintaining the apps & services. Tech stack including: Flutter, React, NextJS, Golang, NodeJS, Android (Java), and Redis.

- Frontend & Mobile Engineering Lead | October 2022 June 2023, 7 months
 Act as an engineering manager and technical leader to Frontend and Mobile development teams. Leading a total of 5 software engineers across 2 teams.
- Software Engineer, Payment Team | February 2022 October 2022, 8 months
 Assist my company in obtaining PTD (Penyelenggara Transfer Dana) certification from Bank Indonesia.
 Build internal web-based tools to help the sales team generate MoU documents quickly.
- Software Engineer, School's Digitalization Team | October 2021 February 2022, 5 months
 Help one of the most crucial apps in my company to be migrated from Golang + VanillaJS to a NextJS app, and launched on schedule to be used by 20k+ schools across Indonesia.
- Mobile Developer, Flutter Team | October 2020 October 2021, 1 year
 Lead a team to build a new cross-platform (Flutter) mobile app from scratch with main features: online payment, student's records & file uploads, student financing, and newsfeed. I act as a mobile lead leading a team of 3. We develop the app to 100K downloads in Google Play Store.
- Mobile Developer, Android & NodeJS | April October 2020, 7 months
 I maintain an existing Android and NodeJS app for student payment. We successfully decreased the number of crashes significantly.

Binar Academy's Full-Stack Class, Part Time | December 2022 - May 2023, 5 months

• Lecturer & mentor

We facilitate a class (10-person, 6-months program) to be excellent at full-stack web development by delivering course material accompanied by live coding examples & mentoring student's final project.

DigiTalent Scholarship's Frontend Class, Part Time | July - October 2021, 3 months

• Lecturer & mentor

We teach JavaScript & React in a 3-months online course to 20+ students in Digitalent Scholarship (DTS) 2021, a program held by Indonesia's Ministry of Communication & Informatics. Course material consists of delivering theory through online class & mentoring student's final project.

RubyH, Indonesia, Full Time | March 2018 - April 2020, 2 years & 2 months

RubyH is an Indonesian software house that helps startups/companies outsource their tech needs. We work with clients including PwC, Midtrans, Akseleran, Transfez, etc. Tech stack includes: React, Redux, ReduxForm, React Native, TypeScript, Apollo GraphQL.

- Associate-level Engineer (Team Lead) | March 2019 April 2020, 13 months
 I code, mentor the team, manage the team workload, and also architect the front-end development. We successfully delivered clients' needs. We also implement TypeScript in our stack, improving our DX.
- Junior-level Engineer | March 2018 March 2019, 13 months

As this is my first company, I learned many practical coding skills. I suggest a crucial insight for Redux state architecture. Promoted as a Team Lead for ReactJs engineers.

EDUCATION

Universitas Indonesia, Indonesia | August 2012 - August 2016

Bachelor of Science (Physics) GPA: 3.29

Thesis: Computational modeling of Titanium Dioxide atomic structure to observe its magnetic behavior in respect of temperature (Curie temperature), which could lead to the development of spintronics material. It is done using Fortran 95.

Just JavaScript by Dan Abramov | Awarded on December 04, 2023

This online course focuses on fundamentals on how to set a correct mental model in JavaScript. (course)

DNS for Developers by Ruurtjan Pul | ongoing

This online course focuses on how to reason about DNS from first principles. (course)

COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT

- 1. Initiator of GEMESH (Engineering Meet and Share), an event at Infradigital Nusantara which gathers software engineers in an interactive, weekly, tech talk. Topics cover a wide range, from SQL to CSS.
- 2. Lecturer & mentor at Binar & DTS programming courses.
- 3. Speaker in "Seminar Akademi dan Profesi Fisika UI" (Academy and Profession Seminar) 2019, talking about minimizing barriers to software engineering for Physics's UI students.
- 4. 2106 points of StackOverflow contribution
- 5. I write about my life and coding experience as a blog and I open-sourced my hobby projects.

This is the end of my curriculum vitae.